Expand your universe.
Jupiter Ascending is a science fiction, fantasy,
action film directed by Lilly Wachowski.
In a universe where human genetic material is the most precious commodity, an impoverished young Earth
woman becomes the key to strategic maneuvers and internal strife within a powerful dynasty…
Caine Wise, played by Channing Tatum.
Jupiter Jones, played by Mila Kunis.
Stinger Apini, played by Sean Bean.
Balem Abrasax, played by Eddie Redmayne.
Titus Abrasax, played by Douglas Booth.
Kalique Abrasax, played by Tuppence Middleton.
Jupiter Ascending is a 2015 space opera film written,
directed and co-produced by the Wachowskis.
Starring Channing Tatum and Mila Kunis with Sean Bean, Eddie Redmayne and Douglas Booth in supporting roles, the film centers on Jupiter Jones (Kunis),
an ordinary cleaning woman, and Caine Wise (Tatum), an interplanetary warrior who informs Jones that her destiny extends beyond Earth.
Supporting cast member Douglas Booth has described the film's fictional universe as a cross between The
Matrix and Star Wars, while Kunis identified indulgence and consumerism as its underlying themes.
The film was produced by Grant Hill and the Wachowskis, making Jupiter Ascending Hill's
seventh collaboration with the Wachowskis as producer or executive producer.
Several more longstanding Wachowski collaborators since the creation of the Matrix films contributed to the picture, including production designer Hugh Bateup, visual
effects supervisor Dan Glass, visual effects designer John Gaeta, standby propman Alex Boswell, sound designer and supervising sound editor Dane A.
Davis and costume designer Kym Barrett.
Other notable past collaborators include Speed Racer music composer Michael Giacchino, Cloud Atlas director of photography John
Toll along with its editor Alexander Berner and hair and make-up designer Jeremy Woodhead, who worked on both.
Jupiter Ascending was released in the United States
on February 6, 2015, by Warner Bros.
The film was panned by critics; despite praise for the visual
effects, the narrative was criticized as confusing.
It grossed $185 million against a $176–210 million
budget during its theatrical release.
The film explores themes of jupiter, space, space opera,
woman director, interspecies romance.
The tone is thought_provoking.